Guide to the National Education Association-Film, Audio, and Video records, 1938-2011 NEA1010.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Educational Material, 1952-2002; Series 2; 103 Linear Feet
  - Motivation In Learning 1983 - Progress and Mastery as a Factor in Continuing Motivation, 1978; Series 2; Filmstrip; audio cassette 5:30 minutes long. (Box 3800, Folder 5)
  - Motivation in Learning 1983 - Published Materials, 1978-1983; Series 2; Contains leader's guides, scripts, pamphlets, and manuals for multimedia program. (Box 3800, Folder 1)
  - Motivation In Learning 1983 - Student Attitude Toward the Teacher, 1978; Series 2; Filmstrip; audio cassette 4:45 minutes long. (Box 3800, Folder 6)
  - Motivation in Learning 1983 - Tape 3: Student Attitude Toward the Subject and Learning Situation/Tape 4: Fear and Anciety Related to Motivation, 1978; Series 2; Audio cassette, approximately 24 minutes long. (Box 3800, Folder 8)
  - Motivation in Learning 1983 - Tape 5: Stimulation Value of Teacher Inquiry/Tape 6: Interest and Involvement, 1978; Series 2; Audio cassette, approximately 23 minutes long. (Box 3800, Folder 9)
  - Motivation in Learning 1983 - Tape 7: Feelings Relative to Student Motivation/Tape 8: Responsibility and Learning, 1978; Series 2; Audio cassette, approximately 23 minutes long. (Box 3800, Folder 10)
  - Motivation Spirit Duplicating Masters, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3674, Folder 3)
  - Motivation Filmstrips - Guide and Scripts [1/2], 1978; Series 2; 3 Audio cassette tapes (Box 3674, Folder 4)
    Separated materials found in Box 3675 File 2 6 Filmstrips
  - Motivation Filmstrips - Guide and Scripts [2/2], 1978; Series 2; 3 Audio cassette tapes (Box 3674, Folder 5)
  - NASSP - Bassett, Tinker, Ives, and Park, 1970; Series 2; Bassett, Tinker, Ives & Park Teacher Induction Program Side A Time: 33 Minutes Microgroove RI2968A Side B Time: 33 Minutes Microgroove RI2968B Bassett, Tinker, Ives & Park Teacher Induction Program Side A Time: 33 Minutes Microgroove RI2968A Audible Beep Side B Time: 33 Minutes Microgroove RI2968B Audible Beep (Box 3662, Folder 4)
    Separated Materials found in Box 3661 File 6 Filmstrip
  - National Association of School Nurses - "Respiratory Function" 1, June 1, 1998; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3975, Folder 10)
  - National Association of School Nurses - "Respiratory Function" 2, June 1, 1998; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3978, Folder 1)
  - The National Automotive Trouble Quiz, undated; Series 2 (Box 4059, Folder 9)
  - The Nature of Change: Conversations With Association Leaders, 2000 July; Series 2 (Box 4989, Folder 2)
  - NEA Bargaining Behavior, Module 2: Dilemmas, Undated; Series 2; VHS (Box 4015, Folder 17)
  - NEA Bargaining Behavior, Module 4: Constituencies, Undated; Series 2; VHS (Box 4015, Folder 18)
  - The NEA Job Evaluation System: Working for You, April 2, 2002; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3996, Folder 9)
  - NEA New Mexico "Senate Bill 99, The Law", undated; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 4022, Folder 7)
  - NEA Parents Ask About Schools - "Are Our Schools Up to Date?" - Show B, undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, 7 1/2 IPS. (Box 3741, Folder 5)
  - NEA Parents Ask About Schools - "A Breakthrough in Education" Reel #2 Birkmaier Language Labaratory xx-1-A/xx-1-A Alternate, undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, 7 1/2 IPS. (Box 3741, Folder 6)
  - NEA Parents Ask About Schools - "Can We Help a Slow Learner?", undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, 7 1/2 IPS. (Box 3741, Folder 10)
  - NEA Parents Ask About Schools - "How Does My Child Learn to Read", undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, 7 1/2 IPS. (Box 3741, Folder 7)
  - NEA Parents Ask About Schools - "How Much Homework is Enough", undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, 7 1/2 IPS. (Box 3741, Folder 8)
  - NEA Parents Ask About Schools - Reel #6 - Dr. Virgil Herrick (last take), Dr. Chester W. Harris, undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, no speed indicated. (Box 3751, Folder 1)
  - NEA Parents Ask About Schools - "Should I Know My Child's IQ?", undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, no speed indicated. (Box 3741, Folder 9)
  - NEA Parents Ask About Schools - "What are Teaching Machines?", undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, 7 1/2 IPS. (Box 3751, Folder 2)
  - NEA Parents Ask About Schools - "Will We Have a Year Round School?", undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, 7 1/2 IPS. (Box 3751, Folder 3)
  - NEA Roundtable 11/18/02, Wright Room, Tape 4 [Audio Recording], 2002; Series 2 (Box 4972, Folder 2)
  - NEA's 401-K Program, December 14, 1995; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 4025, Folder 4)
  - NEA Satellite Seminar, 1/22/1973, January 22, 1973; Series 2; Audio cassette, 1 hour. (Box 3682, Folder 14)
    The NEA Satellite Seminar was a three-hour credit course, conducted via radio, designed primarily for teachers in small villages in Alaska who did not have access to community colleges or other professional development opportunities. This course, offered weekly, was accredited by the University of Alaska, School of Education.
  - NEA Satellite Seminar, 2/13/1973, February 13, 1973; Series 2; Audio cassette, 1 hour. (Box 3682, Folder 15)
  - NEA Satellite Seminar, 2/26/1973, February 26, 1973; Series 2; Audio cassette, 1 hour. (Box 3682, Folder 16)
  - NEA Satellite Seminar, 3/12/1973, March 12, 1973; Series 2; Audio cassette, 1 hour. (Box 3682, Folder 17)
  - NEA Satellite Seminar, 3/26/1973, March 26. 1973; Series 2; Audio cassette, 1 hour. (Box 3682, Folder 18)
  - NEA Satellite Seminar, 4/2/1973, April 2, 1973; Series 2; Audio cassette, 1 hour. (Box 3682, Folder 19)
  - NEA Satellite Seminar, 4/16/1973, April 16, 1973; Series 2; Audio cassette, 1 hour. (Box 3682, Folder 20)
  - NEA Satellite Seminar, 4/23/1973, April 23, 1973; Series 2; Audio cassette, 1 hour. (Box 3682, Folder 13)
  - NEA Spots on "The Great Adventure" - 1: Massacre at Wounded Knee; 2: SixWagons to the Sea, ca. 1963; Series 2; 16 mm b/w film with audio track. (Box 3771, Folder 12)
  - NEA Student Program - "The Job Interview: You've Got to be Prepared", March 19, 1998; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3975, Folder 9)
  - NEA/ACT - Guided Study and Homework - Sound Filmstrip - Stock No. - 387 - 11610, 1969; Series 2; 33 1/3 LP Time: 10 MINS. Part 1 and 2. AUSIBLE SIGNAL FOR MANUAL EQUIPMENT (Box 3672, Folder 13)
    Separated materials found in Box 3673 File 4 2 Filmstrips
  - NEA/ACT - Motivation in Teaching and Learning - Sound Filmstrip - Stock No. 387-11604, 1968; Series 2; Audible 19 Minutes/45 seconds 33 1/3 rpm (Box 3672, Folder 15)
    Separated materials found in Box 3673 File 6 Filmstrip
  - The NEA and Safety, undated; Series 2; 16mm film (Box 3971, Folder 1)
  - The NEA Legislative Process, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3968, Folder 7)
  - Negotiation Training Program #1, undated; Series 2; B/W 16mm film, 30:00. (Box 3861, Folder 1)
  - Negotiation Training Program #4, undated; Series 2; B/W 16mm film, 30:00. (Box 3866, Folder 4)
  - Negotiation Training Program #2, undated; Series 2; B/W 16mm film, 30:00. (Box 3861, Folder 2)
  - Negotiation Training Program #3, undated; Series 2; B/W 16mm film, 30:00. (Box 3866, Folder 3)
  - Negotiation Training Program #5, undated; Series 2; B/W 16mm film, 30:00. (Box 3866, Folder 5)
  - New Jersey Education Association Legislation - Everyone's Job, Undated; Series 2; Audio cassette tape Film (Box 3660, Folder 1)
    Seperated materials found in Box 3675 File 5 Filmstrip
    New Jersey Education Association
  - No Child's Left Behind ...and Other Acts of Random Music, Undated; Series 2 (Box 4933, Folder 10)
  - Nonverbal Communication: Its Impact on Teaching and Learning, 1983; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3835, Folder 6)
  - Nursing Assessment of School Age Children: Using the Nursing Process 1, May 1, 1997; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3978, Folder 2)
  - Nursing Assessment of School Age Children: Using the Nursing Process 2, May 1, 1997; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3978, Folder 3)
  - Nursing Assessment of School Age Children - Introduction Sub-Master, March 25, 1998; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3978, Folder 4)
  - Ole Sand: Talks on Tape 1, circa 1970; Series 2; Sand, Ole P.; Audio cassette. (Box 3682, Folder 33)
  - Operation Jerico, undated; series 2 (Box 4515, Folder 1)
  - Options - On Education: Jim Harris, "Teacher Power" Master, undated; Series 2; Harris, James A.; Magnetic audio tape, 3 3/4 IPS. (Box 3688, Folder 10)
  - Organize Politically to Reform Education (Julian Bond), 1972; Series 2; Audio cassette, 27 minutes. (Box 3682, Folder 37)
  - Organizing for Membership Growth, 1982; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3845, Folder 4)
  - Our Schools Have Kept Us Free, July 29, 1992; Series 2; VHS videocassette, 28:00. (Box 3828, Folder 7)
  - The Organized Profession, undated; Series 2; Audio cassette. Tension pad is detached and tape will not play. (Box 3682, Folder 34)
  - Outside - The - Classroom Management, Undated; Series 2 (Box 4933, Folder 11)
  - Planning and Organizing for Teaching, 1964; Series 2; Filmstrip; 33 1/3 RPM vinyl record, 18 minutes long. (Box 3677, Folder 10)
  - Parental Discipline, 1978; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack. (Box 3685, Folder 5)
    Contains separated material found in box 3681: filmstrip.
  - Parents and Teachers Together (for the Benefit of Children) [1/2], 1972-1973; Series 2; 2 Part I Parents and Teachers Together (for the Benefit of Chidlren) Part II How To Make a Parent Involvement Program Work in Your Classroom 33 1/3 LP Time: Part I 8 1/2 mins. Part II 6 1/2 mins. Audible signal for Manual Equipment (Box 3662, Folder 2)
    Separated Materials found in Box 3661 File 2 2 Filmstrips
  - Parents and Teachers Together (for the Benefit of Children) [2/2], Educational; Series 2; Part I Parents and Teachers Together (for the Benefit of Chidlren) Part II How To Make a Parent Involvement Program Work in Your Classroom 33 1/3 LP Time: Part I 8 1/2 mins. Part II 6 1/2 mins. Audible signal for Manual Equipment Audio casette tape (Box 3662, Folder 3)
  - Parents and Teachers Together (for the Benefit of Children) - No. 1-5 Transparencies for the Presentation of Basic Guidelines for Parent Volunteers, 1972-1973; Series 2 (Box 3663, Folder 1)
  - Parent-Teacher Conferences, 1984; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3845, Folder 6)
    Contains separated material in box 3848.
  - Pay Equity: Where to Start, undated; Series 2; Two copies of VHS videocassette, 18 min. (Box 3828, Folder 10)
  - People Power Does It - Cassette Master C-30 Two Track, 1972; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, 7 1/2 IPS. (Box 3698, Folder 8)
  - The Personal Face of HIV (People with Aids), June 11, 1992; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3977, Folder 2)
  - Perspective for Today, undated; Series 2; 16mm color film, 14:00. (Box 3798, Folder 9)
  - Pit Stop, undated; series 2 (Box 4535, Folder 1)
  - Planning the Evaluation of Educators, 1972; Series 2; Audio cassette Pre-recorded program filmstrip (Box 3671, Folder 8)
    Separated materials found in Box 3675 File 4 Filmstrip
  - The Politics of Learning, undated; Series 2; Color 16 mm film, 24:00. (Box 3861, Folder 3)
    Missing segment of film at splice.
  - Population Institute Presentation to NEA Board of Directors, February 15, 1973; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, 7 1/2 IPS. (Box 3829, Folder 7)
  - Portrait of A Classroom Teacher, November 5-11, 1967; Series 2; Pre-Recorded Program 3-3/4 i.p.s. 13 Minutes (Box 3660, Folder 2)
    Separated materials found in Box 3675 File 6 Filmstrip
  - Preparation of the IEP & The Least Restrictive Environment, undated; Series 2; Audio cassette tape (Box 4031, Folder 14)
  - PR in Professional Negotiations, ca. 1971; Series 2; Filmstrip, no audio soundtrack present. (Box 3676, Folder 4)
  - Professional Development, 11/12/1998 (Box 4033, Cassette data_value_missing_ffb65cb47f31bbd5900041b5300847e2)
  - The Professional Team - Ted Conna/Janet Hankins/David VanKenne/Sharon Luke, 1984; Series 2; Audio cassette tape, 38 minutes, with discussion guide. (Box 3804, Folder 6)
  - Program Development, 1976; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack. Two copies. (Box 3682, Folder 50)
    Contains separated materials found in box 3837: two filmstrips.
  - Program Development (Film Strip Transfer), July 27, 1994; Series 2; 1in magnetic tape (Box 4016, Folder 27)
  - Profiles of Abusive and Neglectful Parents - Corine/Harold/Ruth/Leonard, 1984; Series 2; Audio cassette, 53 minutes, with discussion guide. (Box 3804, Folder 7)
  - The Process of Change - Sound Filmstrip, 1970; Series 2; Pre-Recorded Program Film (Box 3660, Folder 3)
    Separated Materials found in Box 3675 File 7 Filmstrip
  - Public Service Announcements - English - Spanish, April 18, 1990; Series 2 (Box 3989, Folder 8)
  - Questioning Techniques, for Teachers and Students, 1984; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3846, Folder 3)
    Contains separated materials in box 3848: filmstrip.
  - Quiet Too Long, 1967; Series 2; B/W 16 mm film, 28:00. (Box 3861, Folder 5)
  - Quiet Too Long (Transferred), 1967; Series 2; B/W 16 mm film, 28:00. (Box 3861, Folder 4)
  - Rafe, undated; Series 2; 16mm color film, 22:00. (Box 3798, Folder 4)
  - Reading is Around Us, 1981; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack. (Box 3685, Folder 7)
    Contains separated material found in box 3681.
  - Recognizing Child Abuse and Neglect, 1984; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette tape soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3846, Folder 2)
  - Respect- Equality-Hope ... The Journey of a People, the American Teachers Association, Undated; Series 2; VHS (Box 4015, Folder 19)
  - Resolving Classroom Conflict Through Social Literacy - Alfred S. Alschuler, 1980; Series 2; Four audio cassette tapes. Duplicating masters are missing. (Box 3850, Folder 4)
    1. An Introduction to Social Literacy 2. The Nuclear Problem-Solving Process 3. Conquering Burnout 4. Games Students (and Teachers) Play 5. Creating Guidlines for Survival and Liberation 6. Speaking a True Word About Classroom Conflict 7. Collaborative Problem Solving in the Classroom 8. Rebellion in Our Nation's Schools
  - Resource Organizations: Anne Cohn/Shirley Cupery/Helen Howerton/Gail Ryan, 1984; Series 2; Audio cassette tape, 25 minutes, with discussion guide. (Box 3805, Folder 1)
  - Results of the Policy Panel on Technology and Its Ramifications for Data Systems: Definitions of Access: Where Will They Lead Us?, October, 1998; Series 2; VHS Cassette Tape (Box 5081, Folder 10)
  - Results of the Policy Panel on Technology and Its Ramifications for Data Systems: Tracking the Footprints of the Postsecondary Learner, October, 1998; Series 2; VHS Cassette Tape (Box 5081, Folder 9)
  - Review of Educational Research V. 50 1-4, Spring-Winter 1980; Series 2; microfilm (Box 4033, Folder 1)
  - Rich World/ Poor Women, undated; Series 2 (Box 4636, Folder 1)
  - Safe Drivers School, Main + Ends, 1950; Series 2; 16mm film (Box 3969, Folder 18)
  - School Birds, 1957; Series 2; Pre-Recorded Program film 7 1/2 IPS (Box 3667, Folder 3)
    Separated materials found in Box 3666 File 1 2 Filmstrips
  - Schools and Families Working Together, 1987; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3846, Folder 1)
    Contains separated material in box 3848: filmstrip.
  - Schools for the 70's: Discussion - Starter Tape Library Cassettes (Stock #382-11762) NEA - CSI, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3630, Folder 13)
  - Schools for the 70's: The Curriculum, undated; Series 2; Audio cassette. (Box 3686, Folder 2)
  - Schools for the 70's: The System, undated; Series 2; Audio cassette. (Box 3686, Folder 3)
  - Schools for the 70's: The Teacher, undated; Series 2; Audio cassette soundtrack for filmstrip. Filmstrip was not present upon receipt at archives. Tape is separated from reel and will not play. (Box 3704, Folder 4)
  - See How They Learn, undated; Series 2; 1/4" magnetic audio tape, no speed indicated. (Box 3751, Folder 4)
  - Selection and Use of Programmed Materials, 1964; Series 2; Contains filmstrip and 33 1/3 RPM vinyl record. (Box 3677, Folder 2)
    Contains separated materials in box 3678: 3 filmstrip rolls.
    Discarded broken duplicate phonograph record; record was broken upon reception at archives.
  - Selling the Association: Tips for the Association Representative, 1982; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette tape soundtrack, discussion guide, and pamphlet. (Box 3852, Folder 4)
    Contains separated material in box 3849/8: filmstrip.
  - Setting Up a Program - Geri Crisci/Dorothy Ladd/Elaine Krause/E. E. (Gene) Davis, 1984; Series 2; Audio cassette tape, 37 minutes, with discussion guide. (Box 3805, Folder 2)
  - Sex Education for the Handicapped: Preparing Teachers, 1979; Series 2; 2 audio cassette tapes (Box 4032, Folder 4)
  - Sexual harrassment, November 6, 1990; Series 2 (Box 3991, Folder 1)
  - Sexual Harrassment, Undated; Series 2 (Box 3991, Folder 2)
  - Sharing A Lifetime of Learning, 1974; Series 2; Audio cassette tape (Box 3665, Folder 5)
    Separated materials found in Box 3664 File 10 Filmstrip
  - Shots for Your Health - The Fight Against VD, Undated; Series 2; Shots for Your Health Pre-Recorded Program 3-3/4 IPS The FIght Against V.D. Pre-Recorded Program 3-3/4 IPS Shots for Your Health 33 1/2 LP Microgroove The FIght Against V.D. 33 1/2 LP Microgroove (Box 3667, Folder 4)
    Separated materials found in Box 3666 File 3 2 Filmstrips
  - Should I Know my Child's IQ?, undated; Series 2; 16mm film (Box 3969, Folder 17)
  - Side 2 Reading Seminar, 11/12/1998; Series (Box 4033, Cassette 9)
  - Site Based Decision Making: A Guidance & Training Manual, undated; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3977, Folder 3)
  - Speaking for Teachers - Political Persuasion Episodes 3-6, undated; Series 2; Audio cassette tape. (Box 3682, Folder 48)
  - Special Driving, 1960; Series 2; 16mm film (Box 3971, Folder 2)
  - Speech by Helen Bain, 4-20-1970, April 20, 1970; Series 2; Pate-Bain, Helen; Magnetic audio tape, 3 3/4 IPS. (Box 3688, Folder 9)
    Tape ran out approximately 2 minutes before end of speech.
  - State Eduaction Finance Workshop [Audio Recordings] [1/5], 1994 May 19 - 20; Series 2 (Box 4972, Folder 5)
  - State Eduaction Finance Workshop [Audio Recordings] [2/5], 1994 May 19 - 20; Series 2 (Box 4972, Folder 6)
  - State Eduaction Finance Workshop [Audio Recordings] [3/5], 1994 May 19 - 20; Series 2 (Box 4972, Folder 7)
  - State Eduaction Finance Workshop [Audio Recordings] [4/5], 1994 May 19 - 20; Series 2 (Box 4972, Folder 8)
  - State Education Finance Workshop [Audio Recordings] [5/5], 1994 May 19 - 20; Series 2 (Box 4973, Folder 1)
  - The Story of Old Glory, undated; Series 2; 16mm color film, 14:00. (Box 4058, Folder 27)
  - Strategic Planning - Kansas-NEA, February 20, 1992; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3991, Folder 5)
  - Strategic Work Team - Diversity - Education in a Pluralistic Society, 1992; Series 2; BETACAM video tape (Box 3991, Folder 6)
  - Stress Management for Classroom Teachers, 1981; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3846, Folder 5)
  - Student Evaluation/Reporting Procedures: An Overview, 1979; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette tape soundtrack and dicussion guide. (Box 3846, Folder 4)
  - Student Loan, undated; Series 2; 16mm film (Box 3972, Folder 1)
  - Student Self-Concept, 1986; Series 2; Filmstrip with audio cassette tape soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3847, Folder 1)
  - Students and Teachers Together: A Partnership for Gifted and Talented Education, 1980; Series 2; Three-part filmstrip with audio cassette soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3846, Folder 6)
    Contains separated material in box 3848: three filmstrips.
  - A Summer Harvest, undated; Series 2; B/W 16mm film, 28:00. (Box 3866, Folder 1)
  - Supervised Study and Homework, 1979; Series 2; Filmstrip with audiocassette soundtrack and discussion guide. (Box 3847, Folder 2)
  - Support Groups and Services - Henry Giarretto/Leonard Lieber/Saf Lerman/Joan Danzansky, 1984; Series 2; Audio cassette tape, 38 minutes, with discussion guide. (Box 3805, Folder 3)
  - Talk...About Parent Involvement, undated; Series 2; Audio cassette. Audio is unintelligible. (Box 3682, Folder 38)
  - Talking with the Victim, 1984; Series 2; Audio cassette tape, 28 minutes, with discussion guide. (Box 3805, Folder 4)
  - Talks with Teachers About Gifted and Talented Students, 1980; Series 2; Four audio cassette tapes with discussion guide. (Box 3805, Folder 5)
  - Talks with Teachers About Writing in the Content Areas, 1983; Series 2; Four audio cassette tapes with discussion guide. (Box 3850, Folder 3)
    1. Writing and Learning Across the Curriculum - Toby Fulwiler 2. Teaching Content Writing in the Elementary Grades - Elaine Snowden 3. Content Writing in a Middle School - Rhoda Maxwell 4. Content Writing at the Secondary Level - Joanne Yates 5. Writing and Television - David England 6. Writing in the World of Science and Technology - Irene D. Hays 7. Evaluating Content Writing - John Schifsky 8. Developing a Schoolwide Writing Program - Stephen N. Tchudi
  - Tape 1: Watch out for Ollie; The Big Classroom; Skippy and the Three R's, 1953-1961; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 1)
  - Tape 2: A Shoebox Full of Dream; They Grow Up So Fast; The Quiet Revolution, undated; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 2)
  - Tape 3: And Something More; Every Child Is A Winner; Hey Look At Me, ca. 1974; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 3)
  - Tape 4: All In A Lifetime; Are Our Schools Up To Date?; Who Is Pete?, 1961-1962; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 4)
  - Tape 5: The Time of Their Lives; The Bright Yellow School Bus; The Golden Key, ca. 1962; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3838, Folder 5)
  - Tape 6: Time To Teach; Jimmy; No Teacher Alone, ca. 1966; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 6)
  - Tape 7: Johnny on the Spot; I Wish I Could, Kathy!; Emma Belle Sweet, 1957-1962; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 7)
  - Tape 8: School Teacher—Danny Thomas; Mr. Novak, undated; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 8)
  - Tape 9: Measure of a Nation; Influential Americans pt. 1; Influential Americans pt. 2, undated; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 9)
  - Tape 10: NEA Announcements; Good Schools Make A Difference; The Open Mind--What's Right, undated; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 10)
  - Tape 11: Freedom to Learn; A Time For Talent; The Scholar, 1954-1966; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3839, Folder 11)
  - Tape 12: A Summer Harvest; A Chance to Learn; A School Year, 1958-1965; Series 2 (Box 3839, Folder 12)
  - Tape 13: Crowded Out; Discipline; Satellites, Schools and Survival, 1958-1960; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3840, Folder 1)
  - Tape 14: Mystery in N-13; Shoebox Full of Dreams, ca. 1956; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3840, Folder 2)
  - Tape 15: No Reason to Stay; What Is A School; Let's Take a Trip, undated; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3840, Folder 3)
  - Tape 16: The Sword and the Quilt; Impact; The Teacher is Between; Real Sell; Golden Ken Award, 1953-1961; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3840, Folder 4)
  - Tape 17: Training By Television; Teaching Machines and Programmed Learning; Right Angle; Prince Edward, undated; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3840, Folder 5)
  - Tape 18: Schoolhouse in the Red; Promises to Keep; Learning for Life, 1953-1961; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3840, Folder 6)
  - Tape 19: Freedom to Learn; More Different Than Alike; Teaching the One and the Many, ca. 1954-1967; Series 2; VHS cassette. (Box 3840, Folder 7)